Finding Aid for School of Education (University of Michigan) Publications 1880-[ongoing]
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sub-Unit Publications
  - Programs for Educational Opportunity
    - Annual Reports
      - Annual Report (includes Annual Report of the Center for Sex Equity in Schools), [1981/82] (Box 12)
    - Brochures undated (Box 12)
    - Journals
      - Equity Coalition for Race, Gender, and National Origin, 1990-1991, 1999 (Box 12)
    - Newsletters
      - Breakthrough, 1982 (Box 12)
    - Programs 1974-1978, 1990-1992 (Box 12)
  - Project Community
    - Brochures undated (Box 12)
  - Project for Fair Administration of Student Discipline
    - Brochures circa 1976 (Box 12)
  - Rehabilitation Research Institute
    - Newsletters
      - Newsletter, 1977-1978 (Box 12)
  - Renaissance High Project
    - Directories 1980-1981 (Box 12)
  - Social Foundations Program
    - Annual Reports
      - Annual Report, 1981/82 (Box 12)
  - Society for College and University Planning
    - Brochures 1982 (Box 12)
  - Spencer Foundation Seed Grant Program
    - Brochures
      - General 1982 (Box 12)
      - Research in Education, Undated (Box 12)
  - Study of Instructional Improvement
    - Brochures circa 2000 (Box 14)
  - Summer Session
    - Brochures
      - 1947-1974 (Box 12)
      - Home School Community Relationships, 1951-1962 (Box 12)
      - Human Relations in School and Community, 1952-1966 (Box 12)
      - Offerings in Guidance, 1949-1962 (Box 12)
      - Program in Comparative Education, 1954-1957 (Box 12)
    - Bulletins
      - Bulletins, 1919-1970, 6 folders (Box 12)
      - Courses in Athletic Coaching and Administration, 1922-1930 (Box 12)
      - Courses in Industrial Education, 1918-1919 (Box 12)
      - Courses in Vocational Education, 1922-1923 (Box 12)
    - Programs
      - Conferences for Superintendents, Principals, and Teachers, 1928-1929 (Box 12)
    - Schedules
      - Conferences and Courses, 1929-1931 (Box 12)
      - Programs of Activities, 1932-1933 (Box 12)
  - Transition Team
    - Proposals
      - Transition Plan, Volume One, 1984 (Box 12)
  - University of Michigan--Detroit Public Schools Liaison Committee
    - Annual Reports
      - Annual Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 12)
  - Urban Education Program
    - Manuals
      - Workshop to Focus on Teacher Recruitment, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Vocational Education Department
    - Indexes
      - Business Education Index, 1949 (Box 12)
    - Newsletters
      - Michigan Vocational News Bulletin, v. 1-15, 1922-1938, 2 volumes (Box 12)
    - Reports
      - Special Studies, no. 1-9, 1923-1935, 1 volumes (Box 12)
      - Work of the Vocational Education Department of the University of Michigan, 1923 (Box 12)
      - Methods of Teaching -- How Prepare a Lesson, undated (Box 14)
  - Women's Commission
    - Manuals
      - Challenging Sex Discrimination: Training Modules, 1975 (Box 12)
      - On Becoming Sexist: A Self-Study Guide to Sex-Role Socialization, 1976 (Box 12)
  - Business Roundtable Michigan Education Task Force
    - Reports
      - Education Excellence: An Agenda for Education Reform in Michigan, Undated (Box 15)
  - Center for the Study of Higher and Postsecondary Education
    - 50th Anniversary Conference
      - Conference Packet, October 2007 (Box 15)
    - Brochure
      - A World of Difference, 2004 (Box 15)
  - Detroit Public Schools Partnership
    - Photograph Book, 2011 (Box 15)
  - Early Childhood Longitudinal Study
    - Kindergarten Class of 1998-1999 July 1997 (Box 15)
    - Kindergarten Class of 1998-1999 August 1997 (Box 15)
  - Educational Studies Program
    - A World of Difference, 2004 (Box 15)
  - National Center for Research to Improve Postsecondary Teaching and Learning
    - Reports
      - Assessing the Organizational and Administrative Context for Teaching and Learning: An Institutional Self-Study Manual, 1991 (Box 15)
      - Assessing Students' Organization of Concepts: A Manual for Measuring Course-Specific Knowledge Structures, 1991 (Box 15)
      - Course Planning Exploration for Program Self-Study User's Manual, 1991 (Box 15)
      - Design in Context: A Conceptual Framework for the Study of Computer Software in Higher Education, 1987 (Box 15)
      - Designing the Learning Plan: A Review of Research and Theory Related to College Curricula, 1986 (Box 15)
      - Electronic Information: Literacy Skills for a Computer Age, 1986 (Box 15)
      - Faculty as a Key Resource: A Manual for Institutional Self-Study, 1991 (Box 15)
      - Faculty as a Key Resource: A Review of the Research Literature, 1986 (Box 15)
      - A Manual for the Use of the Motivated Strategies for Learning Questionnaire (MSLQ), 1991 (Box 15)
      - Planning a College Course: A Guidebook for the Graduate Teaching Assistant, 1989 (Box 15)
      - Reflection on Course Planning: Faculty and Students Consider Influences and Goals, 1988 (Box 15)
      - Student Goals Exploration User's Manual: Classroom Research Guide, 1991 (Box 15)
      - Student Goals Exploration User's Manual: Institutional Research Guide, 1991 (Box 15)
      - Teaching Tips for Users of the Motivated Strategies for Learning Questionnaire, 1991 (Box 15)
      - Teaching and Learning in the College Classroom: A Review of the Research Literature, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Programs for Educational Opportunity
    - Journals
      - Approaches for Achieving a Multicultural Curriculum, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Newsletters
      - Breakthrough, 1984 (Box 15)
    - Secondary School Teaching Guide
      - "From Jumpstreet: A Story of Black Music," 1980 (Box 15)
- Topical Publications
  - Alumni
    - Directories
      - List of Students Who Have Pursued Courses of Instruction in the Science and Art of Teaching During the Years 1879/80, 1880/81, 1882 (Box 12)
    - Reports
      - Alumni Profiles, 1975-1976 (Box 12)
    - Education Alumni Society
      - Programs 1987-1990 (Box 12)
      - Manuals
        - Handbook, 1985/86 (Box 12)
      - Board of Governors
        - Manuals
          - Handbook, 1989 (Box 12)
        - Visiting Committee
          - Reports
            - Report of the Visiting Committee, 1990 (Box 12)
    - Emeritus Club (Box 13)
      - Directories
        - Emeritus Class Notes: Education Classes of 1939, 1989 (Box 13)
        - Emeritus Class Notes: Education Classes of 1938, 1988 (Box 13)
      - Newsletters
        - Post Emeritus, 1973-1982 (Box 13)
  - Conferences
    - Conference on Teacher Education
      - Programs 1955-1965 (Box 13)
    - EDUCOM
      - Programs
        - EDUCOM '89 25th Anniversary Conference: Lessons from the Past, Strategies for the Future, 1989 (Box 13)
    - Evaluation of Personal Qualifications of Trainees in Professional Programs
      - Proceedings 1977 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Programs 1940-1997 (Box 13)
    - National Coalition for Sex Equity in Education--14th Annual Conference
      - Programs 1993 (Box 13)
    - Summer Education Conference
      - Programs 1941-1966 (Box 13)
  - Development (Box 13)
  - Brochures, ca. 1975-1992
    - 50th Anniversary (Box 13)
    - Histories
      - Sonet Lumiere: Highlighting the First Fifty Years of the School of Education of the University of Michigan, 1921-1971, 1971 (Box 13)
    - Programs
      - Golden Anniversary Celebration, 1971 (Box 13)
  - 75th Anniversary (of the establishment of the chair)
    - Programs 1955 (Box 13)
  - 75th Anniversary
    - Brochures 1997 (Box 13)
    - Histories
      - The Science and the Art of Teaching: The 75th Year of the University of Michigan School of Education, 1997 (Box 13)
    - Programs 1997 (Box 13)
  - 100th Anniversary (of the establishment of the chair)
    - Programs 1979 (Box 13)
- Student Publications
  The Student Publications series includes the newsletter The Ink Well and publications of Phi Kappa Phi honor fraternity. Researchers should consult the Phi Delta Kappa professional education fraternity and Pi Lambda Theta education honor society record groups for more information on student organizations associated with the School of Education.
  - Newsletters
    - The Ink Well, 1945-1949 (Box 13)
  - Student Organizations
    - Phi Delta Kappa
      - Brochures 1976-1981, undated (Box 13)
      - Newsletters
        - Clearing House: Information of the Ad Hoc Committee to Assure Women Their Right to Membership in Phi Delta Kappa, 1973 (Box 13)
        - Newsletter, 1983 (Box 13)
        - PDK, 1980-1981 (Box 13)
        - Phi Delta Kappa News, 1972 (Box 13)
      - Programs 1965-1981 (Box 13)
    - Phi Kappa Phi
      - Constitutions
        - Constitution of the Honor Society of Phi Kappa Phi, 1960 (Box 13)
      - Manuals
        - The Handbook, Undated (Box 13)
    - Pi Lambda Theta
      - Calendars 1978-1982 (Box 13)
      - Directories 1963-1964 (Box 13)
      - Manuals 1944, 1959, 1975 (Box 13)
      - Newsletters
        - Newsletter of the Xi Chapter, 1965 (Box 13)
    - Students for Educational Innovation
      - Manuals
        - Student Information Package, 1974 (Box 13)
    - Undergraduate School of Education Student Organization
      - Newsletters
        - USESO, 1986 (Box 13)
        - You Say So, 1988 (Box 13)
- Archived School of Education Website
  The Archived Website series documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the School of Education. Content includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and course catalogs), and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, and the overall mission of the School. The website series is arranged chronologically, with captures from 2002 and 2003 stored on CD. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - Website capture May 15, 2002, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 2)
  - Website capture May 22, 2003, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 2)
  - Archived School of Education home page, 2010-[ongoing]
  - Archived websites related to the School of Education, 2010-[ongoing]